コードギアス反逆のルルーシュR2 TURN 24　ダモクレス　の　空
TURN 24　ダモクレス　の　空
黒の騎士団
一人残る扇さん
とシュナイゼルの声
と答えるナナリー
ミレイさんとリヴァル
と咲世子　セシル ロイドさん
ルルーシュはC.C.のもとへ
と近づく2人に攻撃
とC.C.
あっ
すでにルルーシュが座っていました
ん？
シンクー（天子?命）たち
あっ
生きてたのか　！！
倒れるディートハルト
うっ　うっ
えっ
あっ
驚くルルーシュ
本当にいいのか？扇
Are you sure about this, Ohgi?
Yeah. I have a duty
to get everyone to safety.
俺にはみんなを避難させる責任がある
しかし
But!
いや俺こそすまないと思っている
No, I'm sorry
I did this to you.
おまえたちを　フレイヤが支配する戦場に
Bringing you all to a battlefield
controlled by F.L.E.I.J.A.
また　フレイヤが
Another F.L.E.I.J.A....
トワミー艦隊　消滅しました作戦は
Twammi fleet, annihilated!
Should the operation...
作戦は継続する
The operation will continue!
このアヴァロンはこのまま後退
The Avalon will continue to fall back!
Keep our distance from Damocles!
ダモクレスとの距離を保て
各部隊は波状攻撃をもってダモクレスにフレイヤを撃たせ続けよ
All units, attack in waves and force
Damocles to continue launching F.L.E.I.J.A.s!
フレイヤの発射装置を持つナナリー
So easily, I...
So easily...
こんなに　あっさりと　私が
ナナリー　次の発射準備ができたよ
Nunnally, we're ready
to fire the next one.
はい
R-Right...
Sekai no owari de
At the end of the world
Umareta hikari
The light that's born
Ima kaze no naka
Now blows in the wind
Kireigoto dake jaa ikirenai
Pretty words alone won't sustain you
Yasashisa dake jaa iyasenai
Kindness alone won't heal you
Ubawareta nowa nanda
What is it that was stolen from you
Kawaranai sekai de
In this unchanging world
Kikoetekita nowa nanda
What is it that you hear
Shikisai no uta
A song of color
Everything is bright...
Kudakechitta yume wo
Let our crumbled dreams resound
Asu no hate ni hibikaseru you ni
At the edge of tomorrow
Sekai no owari de
At the end of the world
Umareta hikari
The light that's born
Bokura hitotsu ni
Becomes one with us
Ima kaze no naka
Now blows in the wind
THE GRIP OF DAMOCLES
戦術が意味をなさない
It renders tactics useless.
だが　しかし！懐にはいりさえすれば
Even so... if I get in close,
they won't be able to use it!
フレイヤはつかえまい！
ブレイズルミナス？！
A blaze luminous!
あんな巨大な
That huge?!
あのダモクレスはもともと絶対の制空権を握るためにつくられたものですから
Damocles was originally built to
achieve absolute air superiority.
このまま高度をあげられると
If it keeps ascending, we'll lose our
chance to do anything against it!
こちらからは手をだせなくなります
くっスザク
Suzaku! Can you break
through those defenses?
あの守りを突破できるか？
やってはいる
I'm trying! But their power output
is in a different league from mine!
でも 相手の出力が桁違いで
この状態なら　フレイヤは撃てないはずだけど
I don't think they can fire
a F.L.E.I.J.A. now, though.
こちらの攻撃も通じないのでは
And our attacks can't get through to them, either.
We may as well be spectators now.
ただの傍観とかわりない
世界はフレイヤという圧倒的な恐怖にだまりこむしか
Is there nothing left but for the world to cower
before the overwhelming might of F.L.E.I.J.A.?
それも平和な状態というのかな
Well, that achieves
a sort of peace, too.
残存勢力をこのアヴァロンを中心に集結させろ
Mass our remaining forces
around the Avalon!
人質ごとダモクレスに突撃をかける
We'll assault Damocles
with the hostages aboard here!
いいんですか？
Sure you wanna do that?
おまえが戻ってきたということはめどがついたんだろう
Your return here means you've
almost figured it out, I presume.
あとは陛下とスザクくんにかかっていますがね
The rest depends on you
and Suzaku, Your Majesty.
シュナイゼル
Schneizel! Are you trying
to kill the hostages, too?!
人質ごと消すつもりか？！
黒の騎士団がやぶれた今
Now that the Black Knights
have been beaten...
まだ負けてはいない！
We aren't beaten yet!
では10分待ちましょう
Then I'll wait 10 minutes.
たった10分！
Just 10 minutes?!
反撃の位置取りをしたから
You're contacting me because you're in
formation to counterattack, aren't you?
こちらに連絡をいれているのでは？
わかった10分なら
All right, then. 10 minutes.
通信を切るシンクー
次弾発射までの10分を高く貸し付けたものですね
That's a hefty loan, considering we
need 10 minutes to prep the next shot.
戦後処理の手をうっただけだよ
It'll save me the trouble of
dealing with them after the battle.
黒の騎士団はもう必要がないと？
Are you saying you don't need
the Black Knights anymore?
集合体としての軍事力になんの意味が？
What purpose is there for
a collective military force?
アッシュフォード学園
ねえ　リヴァル
Hey, Rivalz.
なんすか？会長
What, Prez?
すごいよね
It's amazing, isn't it? Our student council
members are fighting the whole world.
うちの生徒会メンバーが世界を相手に戦っているなんて
それ　いやみですか
Is that sarcasm?
俺がニーナをまもれなかったからって
Because I wasn't able
to protect Nina?
考えすぎよあなたがんばったじゃない
Oh, don't take it so seriously.
You did your best, right?
がんばるだけじゃ
Yeah, I tried, but...
ううん がんばった
No. You did.
アヴァロンが攻撃されます
後ろから？！
From behind?!
きゃあと震動におびえる天子と神楽耶
黒の騎士団
The Black Knights!
必ずや　我らの手で！
I swear I will
defeat you myself!
まわり込んだのか?シンクー！
You snuck around me,
Xing-ke?!
このアヴァロンは　おとさせない！
I won't let the Avalon
be shot down!
シンクーと戦うスザク
シンクー　止める！
Xing-ke, I'll stop you!
道理なきものなどに！
Justice weighs on my side!
シンクーが血を吐いている！
終わりだ！
It's over!
何？！
What?!
枢木！！
Kururugi!
そんな状態で　よく
I'm amazed you can
still fight in your condition!
国を捨て　位にのみ固執する醜い存在になり果てたな
It disgusts me to think that you
abandoned your nation to climb in rank!
おまえの願いはどこにある？
What do you have to fight for?!
自分はただ　明日を望んでいるだけだ！
All I want is a future!
おまえが望む明日など！
Your future is worthless!
不覚！
I've failed!
藤堂さん！
Tohdoh!
隙あり
しまった！
Damn!
ほう～　さすがというべきかな
Ah! I have to admit,
they did well.
第一フロート損傷
Primary float unit, damaged.
Damage level 75% .
損害率７５％
落ちるか　このアヴァロンが
We're falling...
The Avalon is falling!
まだ　中には！
They're trying to get in!
待て待てまて～～い！
Hold it, hold it, HOLD IT!
さあ　俺たちの因縁に決着を！
Okay, now to settle things
once and for...
あっ　俺だってなあ　意地があんだよ～～！
No, I'm not giving up!
I've got pride, too!
という玉城を瞬殺するスザク
間に合わなかった？
I wasn't in time.
中に入られたら
They got in.
白兵戦に持ち込めば勝機がある！
中にはいってナイトメアからおりたシンクー（天子?命）
If we get them into a hand-to-hand
fight, we have a chance to win!
動力制御と通信を押さえ人質の救出に向かう！
Cut power and communications,
then rescue the hostages!
臣遵旨！
Chen Tsun Tsui!
ここまでもてば十分だ
Holding out this long
was good enough.
本艦はこのまま太平洋に着水
Land the ship in the Pacific.
君たちはミッション　アパテ·アレティアを
You all will now follow
mission Apate Aletheia.
ルルーシュ様
Master Lelouch...
これまでつかえてくれた
You have served me well.
君たちの覚悟に感謝する
I am grateful for the resolution
you all have shown.
イエス　ユア　マジェスティ
Yes, Your Majesty.
ミャ～ン
ここで撃てるかな　フレイヤは
Should we fire the F.L.E.I.J.A. here?
ブレイズルミナスを張っていますし
We still have the blaze luminous.
We should wait for criticality.
臨界までは
そうか黒の騎士団にも消えてもらう好機だけど
Good point.
It's a good chance to eliminate
the Black Knights, though.
いや　いけないなこれは欲だ
No, I suppose I shouldn't.
We mustn't be greedy.
ああわかっている
Yes, I understand.
これは俺個人の望みだ
This is a personal request
from me. However...
しかし
ユーフェミア様の願いでもあるんでしょう？
It was also Princess Euphemia's wish,
wasn't it?
だから　俺がやらないと
Which is why... I have to do it.
でも　あれの最終プログラムは環境データをうちこまないと完成しない
However, unless the environmental
data is entered into the final program,
the device won't be complete.
Let me go with you.
私もいっしょに
もう十分だよ ニーナ
You've done enough, Nina.
今の言葉で君の本心を理解した
What you said just now shows me
your true feelings in this.
ユフィのかたきである俺に
You've done enough for me...
For Zero, Euphy's murderer.
ゼロによくつきあってくれた
私は　ゼロを許しはしないたぶん　一生
I can't forgive Zero.
Maybe not for the rest of my life.
でも　それとは別に
But this is separate from that.
私自身の答えを出さなきゃいけないと思ったから
I just had to find
my own answer to all this.
ただそれだけなの
That's all.
君は立派だよ
You really are amazing.
ルルーシュとわかれて歩きだすニーナ
C.C.　無事だったのか
C.C., you're all right?
めずらしいな心配してくれるのか
Well, that's a switch.
Were you worried about me?
大事な戦力だからな
As a valued combatant.
ふっ　だからあれをとりにきた
That's why I came to get this.
では　護衛をたのもうか
Then you'll escort me?
やはり出るのか
You're going out there, right?
ナナリーをその手でうつことになるかもしれないのに
Even though you may have
to kill Nunnally yourself.
ゼロレクイエムの障害になるのならしかたない
If she stands in the way of the
Zero Requiem, I have no choice.
ルルーシュ　恨んでいないのか？私のことを
Lelouch...
Don't you hate me?
ギアスを与えたことで
I changed your fate drastically
by giving you Geass.
おまえの運命は大きくかわってしまった
らしくないな魔女のくせに
This isn't what a witch
is supposed to say, is it?
C.C.おまえがくれたギアスが
C.C., the Geass you gave me...
おまえがいてくれたから俺は歩きだすことができたんだ
What you gave me
only started me down the road.
そこから先のことは　すべて俺の
Everything that followed
was my doing.
初めてだよ　お前みたいな男は
I've never met
a man like you.
C.C.
C.C....
うっ
カレン！
Kallen!
あなたは私が止める！
I'm going to stop you!
さようなら　ルルーシュ！
Goodbye, Lelouch.
くっ
ここは私に任せてダモクレスを！
Leave this to me!
Get to Damocles!
しつこい！
You stubborn!
しかし　紅蓮相手では
But, you're no match
for the Guren!
うれしかったよ　心配してくれて
I'm glad that you care,
Lelouch.
早く行って そして戻って来い
C.C.の目がうるんでいるような
Now go, but make sure
you come back!
私に笑顔をくれるんだろ？
That'll make me smile, right?
ああ約束しよう！
Yes. I promise you!
帽子をとって誓うルルーシュ
必ず成功させてみせる
I have to succeed. This move
has to work, no matter what!
この一手で　なんとしても！
敵ナイトメア編隊接近中
Enemy Knightmares, approaching.
The Shinkirō is leading them.
先頭は蜃気楼です
フレイヤ発射口のブレイズルミナスを部分解除
Lower the blaze luminous from
over the F.L.E.I.J.A. launch tube.
照準は蜃気楼に変更する
Target the Shinkirō!
ルルーシュ　最後は捨て身か
Lelouch, are you throwing your life
away at the very end? How unsightly.
見苦しいな
照準変更　完了
Realignment, complete.
ナナリー　これでおしまいだできるね？
Nunnally.
Now we will end it.
You can do this, right?
はいシュナイゼル兄様
Yes, Brother Schneizel.
ブレイズルミナス解除
Blaze luminous, lowered.
ナナリー スイッチオン
今だよ
Now.
うっ
よし　データ入力を
All right. Entering data.
フレイヤは　刻々とその組成を変化させる
The F.L.E.I.J.A. changes composition
from moment to moment.
その組成に対応する反応をぶつければ
If you hit it with a reaction
corresponding to that,
フレイヤの臨界反応は停止できる
you can stop the F.L.E.I.J.A.
from achieving criticality.
でも爆発までの約１９秒で
But you have to enter
the local environment data...
現場環境データをプログラムに入力しなきゃいけない
within the approximately
19 seconds before detonation.
それにプログラムを完成させても
And even if you
complete the program,
実行可能時間はコンマ04秒だけ
you'll only have
0.04 seconds for it to execute.
平和の　完成だ
With this, peace will be assured.
スザク！
Suzaku!
イエス　ユア　マジェスティ！
Yes, Your Majesty!
ぐわぁ～～～！
今だ！
Now!
原理上は可能なはず
It should work in theory, but...
でも　ユーフェミア様！
Princess Euphemia!
フレイヤが　消えた？
The F.L.E.I.J.A.!
It disappeared?!
はぁ
やった　やりきったの？
It worked... They did it?
１９秒とコンマ０４秒を
In 19 seconds and then in 0.04 seconds?
そんなおもちゃを用意していたとは
I didn't expect them
to have made a toy like that.
今だ！飛びこめ！
Now! Fly in!
ブレイズを突破した？！
They've penetrated the blaze!
やってくれたね
Indeed, they have.
震動で鍵をおとすナナリー
アルファ３に敵機侵入！
Enemy infiltration, alpha-3!
鍵　ダモクレスの鍵が
The key!
The Damocles key!
鍵をさがすナナリー
デルタブロック　通信途絶
Delta block,
communications cut!
第六フロート　制御ルーム　破壊されました！
Float unit control room 6 has been
destroyed! Prince Schneizel!
シュナイゼル殿下！
たいしたものだねルルーシュ
I salute you, Lelouch.
私に最後の策を使わせるとは
For forcing me
to use my final plan.
えっ本当にあれを？
You're really going to do that.
ああこのダモクレスはルルーシュたちをとらえた檻となった
Yes. Turn Damocles into a prison
for Lelouch and the others.
私たちが脱出したあと
After we abandon ship,
このダモクレスそのものをフレイヤで消去しよう
we'll destroy Damocles
itself with a F.L.E.I.J.A.
立派な棺だ
A fine coffin for him.
喜んでくれるだろうかルルーシュは
I'm sure you'll be pleased
with it, Lelouch.
ダモクレスが衛星軌道にあがってしまったら
If Damocles makes it up
into satellite orbit,
ランスロットでも手がだせない
even the Lancelot will be
useless against it.
勝つためにはシュナイゼルをおさえないと
To win, we need
to stop Schneizel.
内部構造は分析中だパスワードのブロックを
I'm analyzing the internal structure of this place.
Have to crack a password block.
何っ？
What?!
ジノか？！
Gino?
ルルーシュ
Lelouch!
I don't accept your Britannia!
おまえのブリタニアは　私が認めない
ここできえてもらおう！
I'll destroy you
here and now!
な 何？このパワーは
What?!
How is it so powerful?!
そこへスザクがやってきました
ジノ！
スザク
Gino!
Suzaku!
ルルーシュ　先に行け
Lelouch, go on ahead!
君には倒さなければならない敵と
There's an enemy you have to defeat
and a person you have to save!
救わなければいけない人がいるはずだ
わかった！
逃がすか！
Right!
You flee?!
くっ
ナイトメアをおりて走っていくルルーシュ
ジノ　どうしても戦う気か？！
Gino, you insist on fighting me?
ああ　自分の中にある　守るべきもののために！
Yes. Because I have to protect
something within me!
守るものなら　僕にもある！
I'm fighting to protect
something, too!
守る？何を？
Protect? Protect what?!
シュナイゼルは管制指令のフロアか？それとも
Is Schneizel on the command
and control floor? Or else is he?
と急ぐルルーシュ
セブンス　シークエンス
Seventh sequence. F.L.E.I.J.A. detonation
point reset to within Damocles!
フレイヤ起爆位置を　ダモクレス本体に変更
ダモクレスもフレイヤもしょせんは機械
Damocles and F.L.E.I.J.A.
are both just machines in the end.
またつくればいいよ
We can always rebuild them.
しかし　トロモ機関にそこまでの余力はありません
But the Tromo Agency doesn't have the
resources for that. Not Rosenberg, either.
ローゼンバーグも
いまや世界中が　ルルーシュの敵だ
Lelouch is now the enemy
of the entire world.
そのルルーシュを消し去ったシステムとなれば
If we offer the system
that destroyed him,
様々な組織が喜んでフレイヤを造ってくれるだろう
there will be all sorts of organizations
happy to build F.L.E.I.J.A.s for us.
それは　テロリズムにつながりませんか？
Isn't that essentially terrorism?
一応　ナナリー様の意見も
There's Princess Nunnally's
opinion to consider, as well.
必要ないのでは？餌の考えなど
And why should you care
what your bait thinks?
まさか見捨てるのですか？
Surely, you wouldn't...
You're abandoning her?!
世界の平和とひとつの命
World peace or a single life...
悲しいことだが　くらべるまでもないよ
Sad to say, one cannot be
compared to the other.
あっ　あぁ
鍵　鍵はどこに
The key!
Where's the key?
私が　お兄様をとめなくちゃ
I have to stop big brother!
と鍵を探し続けるナナリー
ここが橋頭保である
We have to hold out here!
Until His Majesty completes the mission!
閣下の作戦成功まで！
今のルルーシュは　嫌い
I hate what
Lelouch has become.
ナイトオブシックス！
The Knight of Six?!
A fitting opponent for me.
相手にとって不足なし！
カレンとC.C.
国でもなければ　復讐でもない！
You have no country to defend!
Nothing to avenge!
野心のかけらも持っていない！
You also don't have
a shred of ambition!
戦う理由がないやつは　引っこんでな！
Someone with no reason
to fight should just leave!
理由ならできた　約束が
I've made a reason to fight.
A promise.
それってルルーシュを好きってこと？
Are you saying that
you love Lelouch?!
うっ　さあな
Who knows?
ただ 経験というつみかさねは
It's just that I thought it's time I stopped
"accumulating experiences" and started living.
もうおしまいにしようと思ったんだ
人間らしいことをいうのね
That makes you sound
almost human!
さすがは
Well done.
カレン　おまえの勝ちだ
Kallen... You win.
どうでもいいよ　そんなこと
That really doesn't matter.
Goodbye.
じゃあね
おちていくC.C.
勝つとか負けるとか
Win or lose, I never thought
I still had those feelings in me.
そんな心がまだ私に残っていたとはな
鍵は　鍵はどこ？どこにあるの？
The key! Where's the key?!
Where is it?!
私がお兄様をとめなきゃいけないのに
I have to stop big brother!
I have to!
私が
鍵 みつけました
まもなく発進します
Standing by to launch.
Rendezvous point with Sir Hartgren is...
ハルトグレン卿との会合ポイントは　変更ありません
is as planned, no changes.
Course, clear. Ceiling, favorable.
ん？
Please set contact
channel to Victor.
シュナイゼルたちがはいっていくと
待っていたよ　シュナイゼル
I've been waiting for you,
Schneizel.
そうか
I see. I suppose this means
you have me in a check mate.
チェックメイトをかけられたのは私か
ああ　とディートハルト
なるほどね
I see.
おしえてほしい
Please tell me, how did you
know what my plan was?
なぜ私の策がわかったんだい？
策ではない俺が読んだのはあなたの本質だ
It wasn't your plan.
What I anticipated was your basic nature.
本質？
My nature?
あなたには勝つ気がない
You don't have the will to win.
朱禁城での対局黒の騎士団のクーデター
That match at
the Vermilion Forbidden City...
The coup d'état of the Black Knights...
あなたは常に負けないところでゲームをしている
You only play a game
where you know you can't lose.
だから　私がダモクレスを放棄すると？
So, you knew I would
abandon Damocles?
シュナイゼル
Schneizel, this time,
I'm making sure that you lose.
あなたには今度こそ負けてもらう
つまり　私を殺す
Meaning, you're going to kill me.
ホングは大三通路から艦橋をおさえろ
Hong Gu, move from corridor 3 to take the
bridge. The U.F.N. representatives are...
各国代表の　あっ
シンクー！！
Xing-ke!
天子様！ご無事で
Your Majesty! Are you all right?
あの方たちが　助けてくれたのです！
Those people saved us!
ろいどさん セシルさん 咲世子たちがいました
シンクー様私たちはあなた方の味方です
Master Xing-ke,
we're on your side.
ルルーシュを裏切ると？
You mean you've
betrayed Lelouch?
えっ　と不思議そうな天子
私たちはおどされていたのです
He threatened us!
しかし　ルルーシュがいなくなった以上は
But now that
Lelouch is gone...
少なくとも　独裁者を是としないという意味では
At the very least, we can believe
that they think dictatorship is wrong.
信じてよいかと
わかりました
Very well.
はい
決戦はダモクレス内部にしぼられたようです
Yeah. It looks like the final battle
will be inside of Damocles.
扇さんも?あっ 事務総長も
Ohgi is... I mean,
the general secretary is...
かまいませんよ無事だということですね
Either way.
You're saying he's okay, right?
あっ　はい
Y-Yes...
治療をうけて寝かされているコーネリア
結局　兄上は私を殺さなかった
In the end,
Brother didn't kill me.
兄上には執着すべき欲がない
He really doesn't have
any driving ambitions.
世が世なら　卓越する王であったものを
In a more normal world,
he would have made an excellent king.
そこをよみきれなかった私は
I was a fool not to have
read through that, wasn't I?
愚かなのだろうな
姫様
Princess...
そばにはサングラスをかけたギルフォードが泣いています
まだ　私をそのように呼んでくれるのか
You still insist on calling me that?
モニター越しに話すルルーシュとシュナイゼル
質問したい
I have a question. Did you want to
use Damocles to rule the world?
あなたはダモクレスで世界を握りたかったのか？
ちがうよ私はただ皆が望むことを
No. I just wanted to give
everyone what they wanted.
平和がつくりたいだけだ
To make peace.
人の本質を無視してでも？
Disregarding humanity's true nature?
見解の相違だね
That's a matter of opinion.
あなたは今日という日で世界を固定しようと考えた
You thought you could keep the
world stuck in an eternal "now."
だが　変化なき日常を生きているとは言わない
But life without change
cannot be called life.
それはただの経験だ
That's merely experience.
しかし　その連なりを知識というが
But link those together,
and they become knowledge.
やはりあなたは優秀だよ
You truly are superior.
優秀すぎるがゆえにみえていない
So superior
that you can't see it!
そう　皇帝シャルルは昨日を求めた
Yes. Emperor Charles sought the past.
You seek the present.
あなたは今日を
だが俺は明日がほしい
But I seek the future!
明日は今日より悪くなるかもしれない
The future may be
worse than the present.
いいや　よくなる
No. It'll be better.
たとえどれだけ時間がかかろうと
Because, no matter how long it takes,
people will continue to seek happiness.
人は幸せを求め続けるから
それが欲望につながるというのに
Even though you know that will
only feed their own greed?
ははははっ愚かしさも極まったね
Your foolishness
knows no limits, either.
それは感情にすぎないよ
You're too emotional.
希望や夢という名のあてのない虚構
Hope and dreams are just
names for an aimless fiction.
それが　皇族という記号で世界を見下してきた
That's because you're limited
by being part of the symbol...
known as a royal family
which looks down on the world.
あなたの限界だ
俺は何度も見てきた
I've seen it, over and over.
The people who struggle against sadness.
不幸にあらがう人を
未来を求める人を
Those who seek the future.
みんなが幸せを願い抗い続けた
How they all carry on,
wishing for happiness.
ギアスも　仮面も　その根源は
That's why I have Geass.
Why I wear a mask...
矛盾だよ
That's a contradiction.
You, who continually denies the will of others,
他人の遺志を否定し続けた君が
ここにきて人の意志を
stand here now
affirming human will.
存在を肯定しようというのは
もういい私を殺したまえ
Enough of this. Kill me now.
ただ　君もフレイヤで消える
But you will still be
annihilated by a F.L.E.I.J.A.
私たちの命で　世界に平和を
We will give our lives
for the peace of the world...
だからこそ　あなたに俺は
シュナイゼルの肩をたたき
Which is why I have chosen...
ゼロに仕えよという言葉を
to give you the gift of the words
"You shall serve Zero."
プレゼントしよう
とギアスをかけるルルーシュ
君は　最初から私を殺すのではなく
You never intended
to kill me at all!
で 殿下
H-Highness...
しまった
Dammit! Why didn't I realize?
なぜ気付かなかった
シュナイゼルの思考を読んだ録画だと
He recorded that video by
anticipating Schneizel's thoughts.
なんなりとお命じください　ゼロ様
Order me to do whatever
you wish, Master Zero.
くっとディートハルト
シュナイゼル
Schneizel...
自分が殺されるという思い込みが
Your willingness to let yourself be
killed is what led you to your defeat.
あなたを敗北へといざなったのだ
反撃にでるディートハルト
動くな！
Don't move!
ゼロ！あなたの物語は　すでに完結している
Zero!
Your story is already finished!
あなたは　生きていてはいけない！
You shouldn't even be alive!
ルルーシュを撃とうとして シュナイゼルの撃った弾にあたり
俺の存在を否定する権利はおまえにはない
What right have you
to deny my existence?
シュナイゼル殿下
Prince Schneizel...
ご自身の命にすら執着のなかった方が
Who would sacrifice his life
without any hesitation!
これが　ギアスの力
Such is the power of Geass!
ゼ　ゼロ　せめて　最期　ギアスで　私にも
Z-Zero... At least...
finish me, too... with your Geass...
ディートハルト
Diethard...
おまえにはギアスを使う価値もない
You aren't worth
wasting my Geass on.
あっ
ディートハルト死亡
ではシュナイゼル
Now then, Schneizel, will you first
cancel Damocles' self-destruct?
まずはダモクレスの自爆を解除してもらおうか
わかりました
Understood. However,
Nunnally has the F.L.E.I.J.A. control switch.
しかし　フレイヤの制御スイッチはナナリーが
スザクとジノ
たとえどれだけ機体を強化しようとも
No matter how strong you've made
your machine, you won't beat me!
君では僕に勝てない！
言ってくれるね！
We'll see about that!
なに
これが結果だ　ジノ
This is the result, Gino.
いいや　こっちの役目はすんだ
No. I've fulfilled my role.
ブレイズルミナスのシステムを？
He damaged the blaze luminous system?
さあ　カレン！
Now, Kallen!
ありがとう　ジノ！
Thanks, Gino!
スザク　決着をつけるときがきたようね！
Suzaku! I've come to end it.
Our paths will never cross again!
私たちのすれ違いに！
ナナリーのもとへいくルルーシュ
お兄様　ですね
It's you, isn't it, big brother?
そうだよ
Yes.
お兄様の目的は　このダモクレスの鍵ですか？
Are you here for
the Damocles key?
ああそれは危険なものだおまえには
Yes. It's dangerous.
Dangerous to you.
だからです
That's the reason.
もう　目を背けてはいられないから
The reason I can't close
my eyes to this anymore.
目をあけるナナリー
あいつのギアスを破った？
She's broken Father's Geass?!
With her own will?!
自分の意志でか？
お兄様　私にもギアスを　つかえますか？
Now, big brother...
Will you use your Geass on me as well?
Dakuse wa oni
This corrupt world is filled with demons
Seigi wa nanzo to
What is justice?
Tou mae ni aragae yo
Resist, don't just question
Akutoku no hana
The flower of evil
Gizen no yume
Dreams of hypocrisy
Mishi me niwa me wo sashi
Give your gaze to the eyes that see them
Sei mo ja mo wakatareru koto nashi
The line between right and wrong cannot be known
Hikari wa tae taiji no you ni
Light is gone, and you slumber
Kimi wa nemuru yami no shikyuu
Like an unborn child in the womb of darkness
Kodoku koso itooshii
Isolation is what you love
Yui-itsu no mikata to naru darou
It will probably be your only ally
Hitori hitori chishio ni mamire
One by one, stained with the tide of blood
Kono jidai ni umare ochita
You were born into this era
Erabareshi oujira yo
Oh, chosen princes
Tatakai koso shukuen
Battle shall be your banquet
Aa ware wa uruwashii zenchi
Oh, I am graceful omniscience
Ai no haha
The loving mother
Kimi wo umu
Who bore you
Kono chichi ni hagukumishi mono wa
The ones who were raised on my breast
Jigoku no harakara
Are your brethren in hell
Mokushi no in
The mark of apocalypse
Shinri wa nanzo to
What is truth
Shirimosezu uzumoreshi intoku no tane
A seed of secrecy buried where no one knows
Moroha no ken
A double-edged sword
Nuku ha niwa ha wo muke
Turn its blade upon the unsheathed blade
Mamorubeki mono dake wo shinjite
Believe only in what you must protect
Aru ga mama ni kimi wa
And in your own way
Kimi wo hanate
You'll set yourself free
あの日から俺はずっとさ迷っていったのかもしれない
Perhaps I've been
wandering since that day.
名前も　経歴も　手に入れた力も
I was so sick of a world
that never changed.
全部俺とっての本道を見つける道だったのかもしれない
But I couldn't give in
to despair by lying to myself.
だから
Yes... My name, my personal history,
the power I've gained...
ルルーシュだ
今週も楽しんでくれてありがとう
いつも応援してくれているみんなにご覧のプレゼントを送る
Perhaps it's all been the path
for me to find truth.
こちらのケータイサイトから応募してほしい
Perhaps that's what
I've sought all along.
本日中の受付だ
Well, then...
もちろん　特製待受けもあるぞ
それでは諸君　来週もお楽しみに
西暦2312年
統一化を果たした世界の裏で
うごめく歪み
それを断ち斬るべき
ソレスタルビーイングが再び